#### **Profile**

Responsible, organized professional with excellent communication skills and ability to manage multiple projects and tasks effectively. Experience includes software design, development, testing, database design, user interface design, and project management. Software products include Web Applications, Electronic Healthcare Records, Healthcare Solutions, and Airborne Systems. Experience in all development life cycle phases, as well as working in an Agile development environment. Current development environment is Full Stack LAMP. *Available for contract or direct hire positions.* 

### **Professional Skills**

Programming: Full Stack LAMP - PHP (OOP, OOD), JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, JSON, HTML5, CSS, Smarty,

C++, C, MUMPS, Cache ObjectScript, Java.

Frameworks: Zend, Egloo.

Databases: MySQL, Intersystem's Cache Database (NoSQL), Sybase

Report Writing Tools: Crystal Reports, BIRT Report Writer Other Development Tools: Git, SVN, PVCS, Phinx, Jira

# **Professional Experience**

# Incentient, Inc. Plainview, NY

Oct. 2014 - Present

## Senior Software Engineer, Development Advisor/Team Leader

Full Stack LAMP development for Incentient's Smartcellar hospitality web applications - PHP, MySQL, javaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, eGloo framework, and Smarty template engine. Responsible for designing new features, improving existing features, fixing bugs, refactoring sql queries, re-writing PHP code for improved performance and accuracy. Tasks performed include: updating back-end code base to be compatible with PHP versions 5.5 and higher, design and implementation of server-side solution to support multiple languages, implementation of database versioning and migrations using Phinx, bug fixes and general improvements to enhance maintainability and performance. Deployment of Smartcellar application in cloud on AWS EC2/EBS.

As Development Advisor/Team Lead, responsible for advising management on technical solutions, working with development team on the design of new features and products, assisting with the allocation of tasks and management of resources and schedules, and implementing process improvements that ensure that quality software solutions and products are delivered. Coordinated with the development team to create coding standards document, implemented code reviews, and QA test plans.

# The Omnicon Group, Hauppauge, NY Software Engineer – Web Application Development

March 2013 – Sept 2014

Developed in-house web application to manage sales leads, projects, and deliverables using PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, AJAX, and JSON (MAMP). Included reporting features and graphs so management could easily interpret and evaluate business metrics. Responsible for all aspects of project: user interface design, database design and administration, and all aspects of client and server side design and development. Coordinated with management team throughout design and development to ensure that application met all of their requirements and needs.

### Project Manager - Software Low Level Requirement Testing

Project Manager for a contract to provide low-level requirement software testing in compliance with DO-178B DAL C. Deliverables included test procedure documents, test results documents, code coverage results, and peer review artifacts. Responsibilities included the planning and scheduling of tasks, communication of project scope and goals to technical team, and communication with the client to resolve issues, report results, and coordinate deliverables.

#### **Software Quality Engineer**

SQE for radar weather and tracking system developed in C++.

Responsibilities included: Participation in design and code reviews, verification of the review process outcomes, completion of required SQA documentation, review and verification of unit testing results and artifacts, review and verification of requirements traceability. This position required coordination with Software Engineering, Project Management, Configuration Management, and Quality Assurance. This project required compliance to DO-178B DAL C.

### Gap Analysis and Development of DO-178B Process and Planning Documents:

Reviewed DO-178B processes with client's current processes to define the gaps. Developed process and planning documents for QA and Configuration Management, as well as Requirements, Design, and Coding Standards that meet DO-178B objectives.

## **Additional Responsibilities**:

Custom report writing using BIRT report writer to generate custom reports from Jama Product Delivery Platform. In-house Quality Assurance and Configuration Management.

# Senior Software Engineer

### Netsmart Technologies, Great River, NY

May 1999 - March 2013

Designed and developed software for Netsmart's suite of Electronic Healthcare Record (EHR) products. Responsibilities included developing functional specifications, front end user interface design, database design, coding (Mumps/Cache ObjectScript), and testing, in an Agile development environment. As a senior level engineer, additional responsibilities included task scheduling and monitoring, design and code reviews, and training/mentoring junior level engineers.

### Project Manager/Technical Team Lead

Project Manager/Technical Team Lead for the development effort required to update Netsmart's EHR products to attain ARRA Certification. Project tasks included modifying existing features and creating new features to meet ARRA data recording requirements, as well as developing Meaningful Use and Clinical Quality Measures reports required for certification.

As well as participating in the software development effort, project management responsibilities included task breakdown and scheduling, oversight of software development, coordination with functional area experts to resolve questions and issues, coordination with QA to schedule incremental releases for testing, and scheduling of daily Scrum meetings to monitor progress and address any development issues as they arise.

# Lead Software Engineer

Lead Software Engineer in the design and development of Netsmart's Addiction Management product, which serves the clinical needs of methadone providers. Product features included physician's order management, medication inventory management, lab orders, and medication dispensing. Lab orders included the download of lab results from external labs. Responsibilities included coordinating with functional experts to design features, coding, database design, report writing, and testing.

Received Listnet's Long Island Software Award 2005 Top Software Winner for contribution to this product.

Drove impressive improvements in Netsmart's Clinical Workstation Product by coordinating with functional area experts to redesign and develop improved Treatment Planning and Progress Notes features. Effort included developing functional and technical specifications, database design, coding, report writing, and testing.

Member of design team that included resources from software development, client advocates, and in-house functional experts, to design the features required to implement Clinical Workflow in Netsmart's Clinical Workstation product. Participation in team included attending multiple design meetings, reviewing documentation and specifications, and providing support to development team during implementation.

Responsible for coding and testing electronic healthcare billing logic, reporting, and claims production based on HIPAA guidelines: 837 Professional and Institutional Claims Processing, and 835 Health Care Claim Payment/Advice.

Experienced with the development and testing of Web Services, HL-7 Interface, and report writing using Crystal Reports.

# Software Configuration Manager/Software Engineer Robotic Vision Systems, Hauppauge, NY

March 1995 – May 1999 June 1989 - March 1992

As Software Configuration Manager, generated C and Korn shell scripts to create software releases, maintain project areas, and create software version files, coordinated with management and engineering to ensure that customer requirements and new features were incorporated in final releases, supported customer service department when new shipments and upgrade packages were assembled to ensure that all software requirements for the customer were met, and managed the creation and distribution of master diskettes and release documentation for distribution to customer service and in-house testing.

Designed, coded and tested software used to analyze 3-D data for an automated vision inspection system. Responsibilities included customer phone support, onsite training, system installation, system acceptance testing, and product specialization.

#### **Education:**

Suffolk County CC	Java Programming	Spring 2012
New York University, NY	MBA Courses in Statistics	Spring 1989
Hofstra University, NY	MBA Courses in Economics and Accounting	1987 - 1988
Lafayette College, Easton PA	B.S. in Electrical Engineering	1982 - 1986

### **References:**

Alan Tillinghast Healthcare Consultant Former Vice President of Operations at Netsmart Technologies alan.tillinghast@gmail.com 516-982-7127

April Walker Quality Assurance Manager at Netsmart Technologies awalker@ntst.com 631-427-7892

Jim Bennett IT Consultant Former Project Manager at Netsmart Technologies jim@jimbennett.org 646-320-1445

Donna Cresci Partner for non-profit Your Energy Shines dmcresci@optonline.net 631-395-4231